CALLAN MCNAMARA

Fullstack Developer

Contact

0452 530 192 callan.mcnamara@gmail.com

Education

University of Sydney BSci Math and Comp Sci Major

Skills

- Python, Java, C, SQL
- React/TypeScript, HTML, CSS
- AWS infrastructure management
- Interviewing and Mentoring

Extra Curricular

World Tour 2018

I had an extended vacation visiting as many countries as

Slacklining

2016 – Present

I am an avid slackliner, for leisure and meditation.

possible in an 8 month period.

NCSS Tutor

2011 - 2015

I taught web development skills to high school students as part of a 2 week summer camp.

About Me

I am a Sydney based fullstack developer with 8 years of industry experience. My special interest is in writing and maintaining web apps but I also enjoy mentoring. I have a strong focus on web technology and am driven by building elegant solutions to difficult problems.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Veyor, Sydney 2019 - Present

I joined Veyor as a fullstack developer to expand the feature set of their construction logistics web app. My main focus has been codebase cleanliness and adding features in response to customer feedback. I have also been heavily involved in the interview process since I joined.

Senior Software Engineer

Canva, Sydney 2015 - 2018

I worked as a backend developer on the Marketplace team and a lead on the Billing team. For most of my time at Canva I was heavily involved in interviewing and mentoring new engineers.

My major projects were:

- Implementing vector watermarking strategy for contributor images.
- Re-implementing licensing and billing system from the ground up.
- Implementing Captcha for user signups

Software Engineer

Google, Mountain View 2014 – 2015

I worked as a backend engineer on the MyMaps team maintaining their custom metadata store. I participated in on-call and release duties and responded to several production issues. I was a key player in the cross team effort to launch Maps for Google Drive.

University Tutor

University of Sydney 2011 – 2014

I tutored for the first year courses Intro to Programming and Datastructures and Algorithms, and the second year course Database Systems.

Forward Deployed Engineer Intern

Palantir, Canberra Summer 2013

I worked on a facial recognition plugin for their data analysis platform.

Associate Software Engineer

Zeptonics, Sydney 2011 – 2012

I worked on the command line interface for a low latency switch used in high frequency trading.